♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ somewhere in time
and space ♪
♪ mike nelson
and his robot pals ♪
♪ are caught in
an endless chase ♪
♪ pursued by a woman
whose name is pearl ♪
♪ an evil gal who wants
to rule the world ♪
♪ she threw a few things
in her purse ♪
♪ and in her rocket ship
she hunts him ♪
♪ all across the universe ♪
[Pearl]
I’ll get you!
♪ I’ll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ the worst I can find--
la la la ♪
♪ he’ll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ and i’ll monitor his mind--
la la la ♪
♪ now keep in mind,
mike can’t control ♪
♪ where the movies begin
or end-- la la la ♪
♪ he’ll try to keep
his sanity ♪
♪ with the help
of his robot friends ♪
♪ robot roll call ♪
You’re on!
Oh, my stars!
Check me out!
I’m different!
♪ If you’re wondering how ♪
♪ he eats and breathes ♪
♪ and other science facts--
la la la ♪
♪ just repeat to yourself,
"it’s just a show ♪
♪ I should really
just relax" ♪
♪ for mystery
science theater ♪
♪ 3000 ♪
Mm, hi everyone.
Crow, servo, glad you’re here.
Just got this, uh,
notice from gypsy.
- Apparently she’s gotta work on
the main switching unit.
- Huh.
I don’t know.
So in a couple of minutes,
the power’s going to go down.
- Yes!
- Woohoo!
Hey, hey, hey! I know
what you’re thinking,
and no looting this time.
You understand?
[Switch clicks]
- Wow!
- Woohoo!
[Glass shattering]
[Clattering]
[Switch clicks]
All right,
what did you loot?
Well, I broke into
my own room,
and managed to get away
with my tv.
[Chuckles]
I’ll never miss it.
Okay. Tom?
Ah, well, I threw a mannequin
through your window, mike--
wait, wait, wait.
Where’d you get a mannequin?
Well, I keep one
for power outages.
Anyway, threw it
through your window,
managed to get away
with your recycling here.
I’m not a very good
looter, am I?
- No, no you’re not.
- No.
We’ll be right back.
If it goes out again,
i’m grabbing my blender.
♪♪
[Glass shattering]
All right,
what did you loot now?
Loot? No, no looting.
I just accidentally
dropped an anvil into your box
of commemorative plates
oh, hey look.
Pearl’s calling.
Wanna get that?
And then
I will rule the world!
[Laughs]
That needs a little background,
doesn’t it?
The deal is, smellson,
i’m going to rule the world.
But you don’t rule the world
by going at it
all scattershot.
Nope, slow and steady
wins the race, old nut.
So, i’m going to rule
the world,
but i’m going to do it
one person at a time.
[Laughs]
Now, who’s first?
Here...
A mr. Todd gunderson, ma’am.
Ah, gunderson eh?
Uh, todd’s fine.
Todd. Todd, good.
Well, todd...
What do you say? Can I rule you?
Can I? Huh? Can I?
Rule me? Uh, no.
Please?
No!
What if I said i’d kill you
if you didn’t let me?
Uh, i’m sorry, I really
don’t feel that threatened.
Get out of here.
Next.
A mr. Tom servo, ma’am.
Hey, guys! Here I am!
Hey, glad to help.
[Together]
Servo?
Yup, it’s me.
Brain-guy brought me down.
My name was next on the list.
Totally random! It’s weird.
So, tom servo,
what do you say? Can--
what? What? What?
Don’t I know you
from somewhere?
It could be.
I do get around.
The tom jones theater
in branson, missouri.
You tried to steal my purse,
and I beat you within--
no, no, no. Must have been
some other lucky guy.
Well, it’s not important.
Can I rule you?
Sorry, baby.
Nobody rules the tom monster.
Damn, your defenses
are impenetrable.
Brain-guy, send mike the movie
while I figure out
this whole
world ruling thing.
Certainly. Mike,
your movie today is,
if one can measure
these things,
the worse thing to ever
come out of canada.
- Whoa.
- It’s called
the final sacrifice.
[Wobbly digital sound]
Uh, ma’am, may I have the robot?
- Oh, yes, of course.
- They need him for the movie.
So long, toots.
Take me up, curly.
Curly? Why, I never...
[Panting]
Here I am, guys! Guys?
[Mike]
We’re in the theatre.
- [Grunts]
- Come on, dummy!
Oh, me, I don’t give
a flying dutchman
about this production.
Huh, I understand everything
up to the word "a."
He comes from
a long line of greidanuses.
[Mouth echoes]
Hooray! The movie’s closed today
because of snow!
[Crow cawing]
Think maybe this is
a documentary about maple syrup?
You brought the facemask,
you nut.
HE’S CHECKING
HIS BIORé STRIP.
[Humming, beatboxing]
I think the movie’s
going really well.
Yeah.
Don’t worry about me, boss.
The hair on my back
is keeping me warm.
Yeah.
Beth plus jason.
Ray davies?
Ugh, ah man, I don’t know.
I slept weird. Ugh.
Bigfoot for
wrangler relaxed fit.
Randy bachman is being pursued
by sadomasochists.
[Gulping]
No fair, you guys,
I lost my moon boots.
My face is warm,
but my shoulders are freezing.
Nobody leaves
the world wrestling federation.
Come back here,
syrup rustler!
That’s his winter tank-top.
Canadian rules football
is much different.
Yeah, man.
I don’t know, i’m just happy.
Ah, I forgot a mouth hole.
Beethoven’s fifth just
can’t get started, here.
Hi, cindy.
[Gunshot]
Oh, he exploded before
they could shoot him.
Oh.
He changed his name from
I believe in something,
but I don’t really
go to church malcolm.
Oh, great,
the score is skipping.
Oh, come on! One more sacrifice
before we go!
Okay, but this is
the final sacrifice!
Goodie, goodie.
Go away, shane. Go away!
Hey, ron anderson here,
just gotta nip down
and make that movie
real good then.
That’s an illegal use
of a silent consonant.
You know what, this has the
baconey stink of canada
- all over it.
- Already.
[Humming]
I am zombor. Kelly zombor.
I hope his wooden shoes
get iced up and he crashes.
Yeah.
That’s an anagram for
"direct to video."
Seven years
after the credits?
I-- I guess.
Well.
You know what, people
are just dying to--
no!
Sorry.
Well, I better get back
to my grave.
Sun’s been up an hour,
i’m starting to disintegrate.
He was a good hamster.
Hello, dad.
It’s been a long time.
I miss you.
I want to know
what happened to you.
I died.
What?
Oh, a mausoleum with
a finished expansion upstairs.
Oh, this is where
they get all the stuff
to put in t.G.I. Fridays.
How many geeks does it take
to screw in a light bulb?
How many?
I don’t know.
That why i’m asking you?
[Sighs]
Man, he is just poured
into that sweater.
This scene was lit
by an itty-bitty book light.
This is where
i’ve secreted away
all my red sweaters.
Oh, boy.
He’s going to find out
his dad is a rodeo clown.
I don’t care if i’m too old,
i’m getting my batman pajamas
back out of here.
He was made in the image
of an egg noodle.
Well, if i’m going to be
a ventriloquist dummy,
I better learn how to live
in this trunk.
[Grunts]
Now i’m going to settle in
with the book of mormon.
Larry csonka!
[Sniffs]
Ooh, shouldn’t have filed
that sandwich.
I’ve got to find the warrantee
on this sweater.
♪ And I will be the one
to hold larry csonka down ♪
♪ kiss him so hard ♪
♪ i’ll take larry csonka’s
breath away ♪
Some guys can really
pull off leggings.
I can’t wait until they start
the internet.
He’s working on
his bud cort scrapbook.
Ah, i’m glad I don’t have
any friends,
because then I wouldn’t be able
to do this.
Man, i’m 25,
I hope I hit puberty soon.
I know, i’ll call
pretending i’m bob griese.
Ah, finally. Grandma’s head.
No wonder dad lost his money,
he invested in lemon mines.
See cheerleaders, classmates,
teachers I don’t like...
A-ha, here it is.
The transcripts from
the spassky-kasparov match
of ’82.
Okay. Devil, living room,
den, family room,
another devil.
To mike pipper.
Oh, he’s a pipper.
Wouldn’t you like to be a--
no, no!
Man.
Don’t.
[Grunts]
Ah, sex, male. See, I am.
It says, "do not wrinkle."
"Dear mike, I had
a close call today.
"The cult is on my heels.
"The map is no longer
safe with me.
"It is the only copy left.
The others I have destroyed.
"We’ll meet again soon.
Be careful.
Your partner, thomas."
Yes, there’s weight-gain powder
in the fridge.
So it’s near
a ponderosa steakhouse.
I’m gonna color it.
♪♪
[Humming]
Morning, larry.
The time is 6:4.
Delayed puberty awareness
programs, here.
Man, there’s an amazing number
of csonkas.
[Grunts]
So we’re just
watching someone
fritter away
their afternoon here.
Mm-hm.
- Operator.
- Hi, could I have
information, please?
One moment, please.
Now, that’s two moments.
I’m sorry.
Information.
Hi, could I have the number
for mike pipper?
No.
P-i-p-p-e-r.
For what city, please?
- From eaglehat.
- One moment.
Eaglehat?
I’ sorry, there’s no listing
for an m. Pipper.
Oh, okay, thanks.
And the investigation
comes to a close.
Well, I better get to reading
my x-men comics.
Hey, get this caterpillar
off my lip.
Well, larry,
I guess I better get going.
Say hello
to jim kiick for me.
[Door knocks]
Come in.
Mrs. Costanza!
There. What are you studying?
French revolution.
Oh, that looks more like
world war ii.
[Chuckles]
Oh, i’m a caution.
Where did you get that?
I found it in the attic.
Leave me alone, mom.
I’m starting a software company.
Well, don’t work too late.
I’ll lock you in as usual.
What was he like?
Now, troy, we’ve talked
about this before.
I don’t want you to cry
about what is passed.
No emotions.
We’ve discussed that.
Is that why you locked up
his stuff in the attic?
You didn’t want me
to get upset?
You found that--?
Troy, you had
no business there.
My father is my business.
Al louis as grandma.
Oh, troy, i’m sorry.
I only want you
to forget him.
Carry on with your own life.
Yeah, once you get one.
Am I like him?
No, he was masculine
and likable.
Yes.
You’re very much like him.
If i’m thinking
of the right guy.
Man, now my room stinks
of youth dew.
Mvp, super bowl viii
for miami.
Seven years later.
[Car engine failing]
That’s enough trees
for the spotted owl, isn’t it?
Sure.
Uh-oh, the town’s alternator
is shot.
Free pictures of brian mulroney
with fill up.
Oh, and who says there aren’t
any nice homes in canada?
Check it out.
Someone’s scratching
his belly.
Damn!
When it’s above 50 or below 40
it never starts.
Canada is for lovers.
His truck won’t start,
but at least
his tablecloth is dry.
If you lived here,
you’d be in hell by now.
Check out
the linc hayes topiary.
Cool.
[Humming]
Hitchcock’s parade of homes.
Aw, it’s
the came-with-the-frame family.
Water me!
[Coughing]
Hey, another kid
exactly like him across town.
He just finished
his exhaustive
four-volume biography
of larry csonka.
[Clock chimes]
Someone’s hitting a fry pan,
which means it’s 8:00.
Of course the clock’s set
to miami time.
Well, swing choir ain’t gonna
rehearse itself.
Called in
for the night shift.
Apparently auntie never
got laid-off after the war.
Why did he put a laserdisc
in the refrigerator.
Hey, el santo!
Hey!
Ah, let’s see if there’s any
larry csonka movies on tonight.
Can I discipline you?
[Chewing sounds]
Cold crazy bread. Mm.
Really is crazy.
Wait, I haven’t read tolkien
in almost a week.
Script is punched up
by harpo marx.
Ah, a yanni song
is about to begin.
What would
coach don shula do?
[Grunting sounds]
It’s his michael feinstein
signature bat.
Tee-hee, tee-hee.
His head is still
factory wrapped.
Is he a door-to-door
executioner?
Ow! I was just going to
read the meter.
You know it’s spring
when the executioners
start getting in the house.
It’s open. Please.
THE McCULLOCHS ARE HERE.
Can I interest you
in a replacement door?
Canadian villain,
garth vader.
Icky flakes. Ugh.
Ah, that was
a good seven years.
Troy! I know
you can hear me, troy.
I know you have the map.
I want it.
Jesse "the body" ventura
dubbed his voice.
Wow, auntie sent
her jack-booted thugs
to make him lunch.
We just want to cut
your sugar-cane crop.
You thugs, don’t run
with your scimitars.
Dam, he’s got a 10-speed.
Get on the banana-seat bike,
and give chase.
Let’s get out of here.
Hey man, thank your sister
for sewing our hoods.
[Laughter]
And then the drunk guy says,
I can’t help being an idiot,
i’m canadian.
[Laughter]
You’re right,
they’re so pathetic, mike.
[Whistle blows]
Huh?
Enough! There’s been too much
canada bashing for far too long.
I say no more.
Don’t you mean, no more eh?
- [Laugher]
- Good one, man.
They are so stupid.
Stop it now.
Instead let us offer
our northern brothers
and sisters
this song of tribute.
♪ Oh, I wish I was back
in old canada ♪
♪ a land which I never
shall lampoon ♪
♪ how I pine for the ice
covering lake manitoba ♪
♪ and the beauty
that is saskatoon ♪
I got one.
♪ I wish I was stuck
in the hills of alberta ♪
♪ drinking beer with some
big, dumb guy trapping fur ♪
♪ as he scraped
and he chiseled ♪
♪ all the moose dung
off his boots ♪
♪ I would learn
that he’s the prime minister ♪
Oh, stop that.
♪ Oh, I wish I was in the land
that gave us peter jennings ♪
♪ alanis morissette,
mike myers too ♪
♪ no, I take that back
I wouldn’t go there ♪
♪ even in you paid me ♪
♪ oh, canada, you are a place
I must eschew ♪
Now this is not in the spirit
that I intended.
Oh, come on. Give in.
I mean, after all, they gave us
ed the sock and rush.
Yeah, what are you defending?
They’re such feebs.
- Okay, i’ll try.
- All right. Good man.
♪ Oh, I wish I was blowing up
prince edward island ♪
♪ going on to bomb ontario ♪
♪ the destruction of canada
and all of its culture ♪
♪ is by far
my favorite scenario ♪
Okay, that’s a little strong.
You might want to back it down.
No, no you were right, mike.
This is much more fun.
♪ Just where the hell does
canada get off ♪
♪ sharing a border ♪
♪ with countries
far superior to it? ♪
Yikes.
♪ Why you lousy, stinkin’,
francophonic, ♪
♪ bacon loving bastards ♪
♪ your country’s
just a giant piece of-- ♪
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, easy!
- Okay, I think that’s enough.
I think we going to cambot.
Okay, thanks.
- All right.
- Wow.
I have no
sense of proportion.
I’m a disgrace to my uniform.
No, that’s okay.
Now, calm down.
Now, we mustn’t hate.
Mustn’t hate.
At least so overtly.
Exactly right. Must disguise
our hate just a little.
We’ll be right back.
Ssh, ssh, it’s okay now, dudley.
- Calm down. Calm down.
- Pardonnez-moi.
Pardonnez-moi.
♪♪
Seven years later.
Dental hygienist of the week.
Yeah, once he gets it started,
he’s going to drive it
to the front yard,
take a couple of tires off,
and let it rust
next to the old freezer
sitting on the front lawn.
Ah.
In my work
for a bloodthirsty cult,
I depend on my gran torino.
I think his menace is undercut
by the "baby on board" tag.
Hey, I think your cameraman’s
stuck in the door.
See?
CAN YOU IMAGINE HOW MANY
POTATO OLé CONTAINERS
are on the floor of that car?
This music is really more suited
to plate spinning.
Kind of a mazurka.
I’m losing track
of the crappy vehicles here.
Crank the molly hatchet
and let’s roll!
[Radio chatter]
I’m sherry.
This is carol dolan,
and i’ll be back.
Aw, now I have to
listen to as it happens.
Honk! Honk! On your ass!
Oh, I love trash--
ow, oh, god.
Maybe it’s the cheap
canadian gas they’re using.
Just can’t get up any speed.
Damn you, peewee!
Hi, i’m billy the building.
[Laughs]
Unfortunately,
the truck’s making a delivery
right back to the cult.
Well, let’s just
go get some bullwhips
and pose for mapplethorpe.
Yup.
Huddled in a pile
of dirty laundry,
it’s just like home.
It sounds like
video-poker music.
And they take refuge
in the anne murray
national forest.
Beautiful, isn’t it?
I think he’s
the tin drum kid.
He’s the kind of clown
who puts $1.87 of gas
in his truck.
Help me, oh,
saint larry csonka.
Well, it went further
than it usually does.
Like a... [coughs]
Rock.
Another human being.
Oh, i’m in for a beating.
What the hell?
I’ve always been
back here, remember?
What are you doing
back there, kid?
I...
I’m laundry.
I needed a ride.
Is he a makeupless clown?
Why don’t you get in the cab?
It’s much
more comfortable there.
Actually, I bet it isn’t.
So, uh, eh then, eh?
[Coughing]
Eh.
Don’t you love
our healthcare system?
Here, put this on.
- It’s made of lunch meat.
- Thanks.
Know anything about motors?
No, sir. Not really.
I know all the songs from
once upon a mattress though.
Let’s have a look.
Are you gonna be a mountie
or a fishing guide
when you grow up?
- Where are you heading?
- Liquor store.
Looks like
i’m heading nowhere.
I see the problem.
The gas line’s loose.
You’re getting behind
the steering wheel,
and crank her over
when I tell you.
He’s wearing fashions
by mac davis.
I’ll just, uh,
pour my garbage in here.
Now!
Kaboom!
Didn’t barbara mandrell
have hair like his at one point?
I think so. Yup, yup.
Put the pedal
all the way down.
Hm, dare I?
[Engine struggling]
Better check this oil here.
Yep, 10w-30.
[Sizzling]
Ooh, his hair’s on fire.
Keep her going, kid!
Okay, bring the brats out.
[Laughs]
Outwitted my truck again!
- WHAT’S YOUR NAME, LADDIE?
- TROY McGREGGOR.
I’m rowsdower.
Zap rowsdower.
Well, my name
is bill shtinkwater.
Rowsdower-mobile away!
And together they fought crime
throughout southwestern alberta!
So, rowsdower,
is that a stupid name, or...?
- Uh, fill her up.
- Yup.
You stay here and i’ll get you
a chocolate bar, okay?
- Thanks.
- Buy me anything in there
with larry csonka on it.
I’ll pay for it.
Shoot, i’m in canada.
Operator, give me the police.
And the cops pick up
their zap rowsdower hotline.
Yes, office, I found this kid
in the back of my truck.
And play in the front seat.
♪ Roll on, big mama,
the highway ♪
How should I know? Ask him.
Ew, gotta get
this dead woodchuck out
from under the seat.
Ew, pooey.
Look, you’re going to
send someone to pick him up?
What do they think
they’re in idaho?
Hey, i’ve got 89 cents
worth of cans back there!
Zap actions-dower.
[Gunshots]
My hood wicks moisture
from my face.
Um, eat my dust.
I don’t know.
Do these pants
go with this sweater?
You know, he blends in.
He looks like a sack of garbage.
Mm-hm.
[Grunts]
This is no time for zymurgy.
Hey, just don’t shoot at me
for a couple of minutes, okay?
Thanks.
If this doesn’t work,
i’ll throw balls of carp dough.
You want us
to pick that up for you?
I knew there was an upside
to being an alcoholic.
Can you take those
to recycling? Thanks.
Canadian mannix!
Uh, so, you wanna
hit the brakes, there, or not?
Oh, i’m so relaxed right now.
♪♪
Rowsdower, I can explain.
Those men
were trying to kill me.
Yeah, tell it
to my acid-washed jeans.
Do you have any idea
what kind of people
you’re dealing with?
They’re from saskatchewan.
No.
- It’s a cult.
- They worship blue oysters.
They want to rule the world.
How do you know that?
I’ve been around, kid.
- And i’ve been a square kid.
- No.
Tell me more about them.
Their faces
are lumpy and whiskered.
Oh, wait, that’s me.
The race
ruled this land once.
They ruled this one acre
for about a week.
Nobody knew.
The race
of the ziox civilization.
- Ziox?
- Wasn’t that a sandwich cookie?
My dad wrote about them.
Bto was such
a great band, man.
Look.
I’m about to puke, kid.
You might want to clear out.
Look at the writing.
It’s ancient.
Old as the crumbs
in your moustache.
Where does this lead to?
Well, nobody knows
for sure...
Except my dad, but um...
I disappointed him.
He was killed
seven years ago.
And I want to know
why he died.
This map is my only lead.
Yeah, hang on. [Burps]
Go to sleep, kid.
I’m taking you home
in the morning.
Oh, I think he’s taking him home
in the morning. Yeah, yeah.
Yup.
Rowsdower?
[Laughing]
Yeah?
Why do I feel like
having haggis?
- Have you always been a--
- hopeless drunk.
Drifter?
Rowsdower, could you
put out my head?
No.
Oh.
Well, what were you before?
Well, I used to give plasma.
You might know me from that.
- I was a--
- a chippendales dancer.
A businessman.
What happened?
Well, I switched to beating up
annoying kids with beer bottles.
Go to sleep, kid.
You’re harshing my buzz.
Huh, now is this touching
or boring? I can’t...
Really...
Rowsdower.
Now that is a darling
maxi skirt.
[Yawns]
Rowsdower.
Wow, I dreamt I was stuck
with a chunky backwoods loser
named rowsdower-- aah!
[Coughs] I think
my voice changed overnight.
Good morning.
So you gonna get us
out of here?
I’ll get us out of here.
Then we’ll stall
50 yards down the line.
Why were you going to
turn me over to the cops?
Because I like to keep
my nose clean.
My body suffers
for it, but...
Helping a runaway kid
can get me in big trouble.
I’d love for you to meet
the people in my youth group.
Rowsdower?
Have you ever bathed?
Will you help me find
what’s behind the map?
Oh, I don’t go
map finding behinding.
You should be in school.
Not running around
hunting down lost civilizations.
Besides, the map
could be a fake.
A fantasy of your old man’s.
Why do you think those men
were following us yesterday?
Ah, they thought I was that guy
from due south.
Don’t you see?
They were after this.
Rowsdower’s got one
of screendom’s best rear ends.
Mm-hmm.
You give me a hand now, kid.
Rowsdower!
Do you know how fast
you were going, rowsdower?
Come on.
Come on, baby.
Don’t let me down.
I won’t, rowsdower.
[Engine turns over]
Watch out, kid.
Rowsdower-er-er-er.
Damn.
You’re going to drive
while I push at the front.
Start out slow.
When you get up some speed,
floor her. Got it?
And i’d like
to thank dan aykroyd
for doing that last line.
Go!
Fudge.
Children and pregnant women
should not watch this scene.
You know, in fact, no one
should really watch
any of these scenes.
- Yeah, you’re right.
- I agree.
This is like
when our nursing home
volunteer bus broke down.
[Explosion]
Wow!
Sounds like rowsdower’s heart
just exploded.
[Heavy panting]
I don’t think
that was a very good idea.
Shut up.
We’re in for a long walk.
- We’re gonna walk?
- Well, it’s not my fault!
You’re the one
that got us into this mess.
You stay here
while I go get us some water.
- I’ll go.
- Can you carry me?
Canteen’s in the cab.
AND THE CAB’S DOWN
AT COLUMBUS AND 77th.
And if you find a package store,
get me some yukon jack.
Thanks for the ride, mister.
Well, I try to work out,
but it just gets hard.
♪ Getting water
for rowsdower ♪
♪ rowsdower wants me
to get water for him ♪
[Sniffs]
Ew, nature smells.
Mike, is there any way
I could hop into the movie
and dump this kid’s books?
Oh, I only wish.
Somebody covered
their tomato plants.
Let’s see what my cap’n crunch
treasure map says.
[Growls]
The three baguettes.
[Grunts]
♪ Rowsdower, rowsdower,
rowse-a-rowse-a-rowsedower ♪
♪ bowse-a-bowse-a-bowesdower ♪
♪ sabidi-sabidi-sowsdower ♪
♪ bippity-boppity-bowsedower ♪
♪ boppity-doppity-dower-rowse ♪
♪ dower ♪
Somebody’s breaking
shredded-wheat biscuits.
Okay, I dropped the canteen,
and I got lost.
Right on schedule.
Ah, next I have to fall,
break my ankle,
be attacked by coyotes,
and buried by a bear.
[Howling]
Take a left at the tree.
That helps!
♪♪
Bad news, losers.
We won’t be in today
because bobo ate a bad can
of canadian bacon,
and he came down
with hockey hair,
and now we’ve all got it.
Lady? Lady.
Can I watch power rangers?
Well gee, pearl,
that’s too bad.
I guess that means
it’s contagious.
Oh, i’m sure you guys
will be fine.
I mean, we live with the ape,
so when he gets hockey hair,
we all get hockey hair.
Don’t worry.
The-- the doctor says
I have to have more whoppers
and malted milk balls.
Yes, yes, dear.
Oh, for crying--
it’s an airborne virus. Sheesh.
Mike, what’s your deal?
How come you don’t have it?
Oh, I had it once already
from 1982 to 1992.
Once you get it once,
you can’t get it again.
Huh.
Oh, no.
You guys got it too, huh?
Well, the best thing is to
just let it run its course.
Well, I think it’s great!
I’ve never felt so masculine.
I feel like guy lafleur.
It’s time...
For my hourly ben and jerry’s.
Huh, I have this intense
craving for zubaz.
Yeah, you’re gonna get that.
[Alarm buzzes]
- Oh, the movie’s playing.
- Oh, sherry!
- Whoa, woozy.
- Sorry, you guys.
Troy!
It’s the canadian nick nolte.
Troy, where are you?
Mr. Aikman!
Hey, mister,
have you seen rowsdower?
Ah, hey.
- Over here.
- What?
Look what I found.
What is it?
It’s a tunnel.
Yeah, right.
That is a classic
rowsdowerism.
A bug! Yuck!
You’re going to throw me
down there, aren’t you?
Yeah, not matter where he goes,
he finds a basement to dwell in.
Excuse me.
- Wow.
- These are really cheap sets.
[Lighter flicks]
This tunnel must have been dug
hundreds of years ago.
I sensed that with my hair.
My hair is an elaborate
network of nerves
constantly processing
information.
This tunnel is on the map.
Huh?
I was right.
The map is real.
Map israel?
I believe israel has been
fairly well mapped already.
Stop.
It’s an evil porky pig.
The puking buddha.
Blech, I hate-- what is that?
I have hair in my mouth. Blech.
Whoa, not there, kid.
Sensitive area.
Never climb
in people you don’t know.
Troy?
Are you dead,
because if you are,
i’m gonna take off.
Firewood for sale.
I guess they thought he was
a baby harp-seal or something.
The just-about-to-sneeze god.
Wow!
I really don’t understand.
You trespassed
on charlton heston’s place.
We bagged our own heads
and saved!
- Give up your hockey hair!
- Never!
You...
You.
So you’ve not
forgotten me, rowsdower.
We meet again.
For the final time,
i’m afraid.
Red grooms’ dracula.
My hawkwind
album cover will help.
Nope, nothin’.
I don’t get it.
Come on, kid.
Give us a hardy "rowsdower."
- Dad!
- That’s my favorite
jack lemmon movie.
You were here.
Weren’t you?
Where’s the boy?
Could you squat down?
I was trying to get you
in the face actually.
- The boy, rowsdower.
- The boy.
He went into
the cave with you.
He has the map. I want it.
I don’t know!
Look into your heart, eh?
We’re going to make you drink
something other than beer.
It’s a cult that worships
georgia o’keeffe.
Hey, look, milk duds!
They never go bad!
His arm sinks in
up to the elbow.
Now give me your lunch money.
Look at that.
Look what you did. Look!
He could easily be
in lynard skynard.
You don’t control me.
This has controlled
your entire life,
you drunken fool.
- Hey, bra strap.
- You’re crazy.
No, i’m not crazy.
I shall see the world ruled
by the only race
that was created in perfection.
- Mm-hm.
- Huh?
They’ll be no place
for the weak.
The ugly.
Vermin like you.
Go to hell!
Or at least edmonton!
Our day of conquest
is oncoming.
I’m sorry, what did you say
about burton cummings?
What do you mean?
That is why you came back,
isn’t it?
You left your albums
at my place.
On a day soon,
an hour of darkness,
our god will accept
a human sacrifice.
Or you. I’m kidding.
This one death
will provide me with an army
of invincible warriors.
- He’s got a goiter.
- Millions of lost souls
- stop spitting.
- Trapped deep beneath the earth
will rise from their grave
and side with me!
You use too much moose.
I shall rule the world.
Take him out to the woods
and kill him.
And take away his blow comb.
Spread out. Find the boy.
Sir, um, should we pick a place
to meet back, or...
I guess not then. Okay.
Yup.
The ancient civilization’s
toilet keeps running.
A treasury
of sergio aragones sketches.
Cool.
Oh, I will have this painted
on the side of my van someday.
Hello?
You, uh, got a preference
about where you’d like us
to kill you, eh?
Now, tomorrow’s casual day.
I think i’m going to wear
a yellow t-shirt.
Ah, i’ve escaped-- aah!
Cripes, he rolled
out of bounds.
What is this obsession
with not showing us
who’s getting into
what truck?
I don’t know.
He’s got a funny tan line.
Yeah.
Oh, no, they’ve got a chevy.
They’re so dependable!
Quick, climb a tree.
Trucks can’t climb trees.
Ooh, you know if you hit
a rowsdower,
you get to keep it.
The meat’s a bit gamey,
but it’s good for sausage.
[Tires squealing]
Uh, i’m okay.
Want to try again?
Grass stains.
When you’ve got cults,
you’ve got to have tide.
Dear counselor troy,
I waited at denny’s,
but you didn’t meet me.
Dear agent scully,
did not appreciate
your lawyer’s tone.
And so, it is
with a heavy heart
that I must resign
from chess club.
Where our token crosses...
The city is located.
Hmm?
Man, I solved myst
in ten minutes,
why can’t I do this?
This is a passive sentence,
I better alert my english club.
Back! Back,
you silverfish, back!
[Grunts]
I can see why quebec wants
to be separate from all this.
Mm-hmm.
He was raised
by a family of moles.
Wait, I have an appointment
to get beat up.
Look like a twig.
Oh, that shouldn’t be hard.
Sir, you have a hole
in your shoe. Oops! Ssh.
He’s built like
a woman phy-ed teacher.
My shirt is charcoal,
that’s basically black.
This is just like when they
bury me every week at school.
And give me pink belly,
and hang me from the goal post,
and shave my head,
and magic marker my weenie,
and stuff me in my locker.
[Monkey noises]
[Gunshot]
Must slip back
and sell candy bars for band.
Uh, i’m just a bush.
You may want to pan off me.
What the-- hey,
I had a bead on a good eh.
Eh, eh, eh...
[Machine gun fire]
[Humming olympic theme]
Gilles, no!
Not etienne!
I’m in no particular hurry.
The cult’s got their schedule,
I got mine.
Hey, are they after me?
Zut alors!
Je suis mort!
- Hey, boys in the hoods!
- Ah, man.
Drop dead.
Mike, would you say these guys
are in a heavily forested area?
Uh, yeah sure.
Would you call these
the deep woods?
Yeah.
Because-- because when
you’re in the woods,
you can’t beat the reliable,
reasonably priced
mosquito repellant "off."
[Laughs]
Man, you never even
saw that coming, did you?
- Wait, it’s me!
- I know.
Ah, they’re eloping.
Ugh, this is just like
when I almost missed
my "teens encounter christ" bus.
Come on,
it was like 30 yards.
Yeah, my hair’s a mess.
So what?
You were one of them?
An uncooked
bratwurst with hair.
[Panting]
I was.
I was only part-time,
and I got laid off.
Years ago.
Why?
Let me die first,
then i’ll tell you.
It started
with the nightmares.
[Rhythmic humming]
Then drums.
They were calling me.
Wow, nobody ever calls me.
It was satoris,
he started it all.
How?
He’s psychotic.
Too many people
underestimated him,
and died mysteriously.
Hold on, i’m having a series
of elaborate heart-attacks.
Is that how
my father was killed?
I’m not telling.
I don’t know.
Ugh, now it’s
turned into a stroke!
Satoris found out
I was only a half-blood.
Soon after, he threw me out.
I-- ssh.
Oh, it’s just a jackalope.
Let’s get out of here.
This way.
HMM, THAT’S A LITTLE TOO MUCH
DéCOLLETAGE FOR ME.
Ah, any given weekend
in canada.
Sides of his heart
are blowing out like old tires.
[Tire popping sounds]
[Panting]
Rowsdower!
This is fun!
They’ve stumbled upon
geddy lee’s birthplace.
Okay.
I guess we’ve had it.
I probably only had about
three more months anyway.
Not yet.
It’s the wizard of id biathlon
hey it looks like
their tin roof rusted.
All right, abraham lincoln,
stop writing on that damn shovel
and come out
with your hands up.
Oh, this is no big deal.
It’s how I get through
every school day.
Winnipeg confidential.
I should tell you that I wheeze
loudly when i’m scared.
[Wheezing]
Uh, guillaume, this is my place.
Do you mind?
Man, they’re bound
to smell me.
[Gasps]
D’oh.
A merde. Mon pied!
Damn, broke a heel.
Guy upstairs
had bad enuresis.
I’ll say.
Ugh, i’ve been pulling ziox
double shifts all week.
It’s killing me.
Ugh, I haven’t been this tense
since mock u.N.
Is it possible to trash
a garbage house.
This was grandma’s
hunting shack.
Listen.
[Crow cawing]
- It’s heckle!
- No, it’s clearly jeckle.
Oh, you’re right.
Hmm, they shot
a pair of snowshoes,
and had them stuffed
and mounted.
- Food!
- Yeah, no beer though.
More food!
What the hell
are you doing here?
We were eating your food.
Against the wall.
It’s gordon lightfoot
at home.
Cursed cult leader
send you heres by me?
[Imitating accent]
You know him?
Get ’em up!
Splatter your brains
all over this place.
No, as a matter of fact,
we just escaped from him.
Then what’s that there mark
doing on your shoulder there?
IT’S A LONG STORY.
McGREGGOR, TELL HIM.
- McGREGGOR?
- GREGGOR!
- TROY McGREGGOR?
- IT MUST HURT.
Thomas’ son?
Yeah.
- Did you know him?
- Know him? He was delicious!
♪♪
My name’s pipper.
Mike pipper.
Your dad and me were partners
in archaeology.
Pipper partner.
Many digs we did together.
[Grunts]
Pipper digs.
Good man he was, your dad.
[Laughs]
Always laughing.
Stubborn though.
Another helping
of filth for you?
What happened to him?
I jerked him.
- I’ll tell you.
- Okay.
The last year
your father and I were together,
[grunts]
We was searching
for a lost civilization.
Ziox civilization?
- That’s right.
- Yeah.
We made calculations
as to where the remains
of their city
might be located.
That’s where
we ran into satoris’ cult.
By the way,
I hates that rabbit.
They wanted our information.
Thomas was too stubborn,
so they killed him.
Poor old thomas.
Could I drink him? No.
Fled here.
This was one of
our base camps.
Lived here ever since.
What do you know
about satoris?
To understand him,
you must know about the ziox.
Ziox,
now with lapitithamine.
Now, thousands of years ago,
long before the indians,
- yeah.
- This land was inhabited
by the ziox.
No it wasn’t.
They’re a highly
intelligent race.
Far advanced in science
and architecture and literature.
No they weren’t.
- They built a huge city.
- No they didn’t.
Far grander than anything
the old romans or the egyptians
had ever known.
The buildings were covered
in gold and silver.
Matted hair.
In the center,
they built a temple
to praise their god.
Then they put a bottle brush
down my throat.
It’s all gone now.
Erased from existence.
- How?
- No, no, don’t encourage him!
- Gee whiz.
- It is a mystery.
As the legend goes,
there was a period
of great wealth.
Brought discontentment
to the people.
- People began to fear.
- Mm. Good dope.
- Fear brought superstition.
- Yeah.
So they built an idol.
Well, their god cursed them
and flooded the land
with a rainstorm
that last a full month.
Their basements got wet.
Soil became so soft,
city sank
into a huge quagmire.
Wait, i’m a huge quagmire.
Survivors were doomed
to roam the earth.
That’s-- this cult is all
that’s left of them.
Hey, what’s this a pile of?
Oh, crap. That’s right.
Satoris believe in the idol.
He thinks that by sacrificing
someone to it,
it’ll provide him with an
invincible army
that can conquer the world.
Except that if
the idol’s ever destroyed,
the old city will return
to its former glory.
It’s a symbol of good.
Mean the end
to satoris’ power.
Uh, these are all legends,
of course.
- Wait a minute.
- I have a gag in my pocket.
- Look.
- Ooh, what is that?
Give me that, varmint.
Your father made this.
Didn’t do a very good job.
We found the original
in a secret chamber
not far from here.
We know.
I translated the sentence
with the help
of my father’s notes.
"Where our token crosses,
the city is located."
What does it mean?
It means "ooh, i’m gonna hog-tie
that varmint."
[Jabbering]
He’s playing
connect the gods.
♪ Come and sit by my side
if you love me ♪
♪ do not hasten
to bid me adieu, ooh ♪
Ooh, I needs an eraser!
Here’s the plan,
my army of trained rats
will lead the charge,
and my scabies
will protect our flank.
Well...
- Pipper cam.
- It’s a symbol!
Emperor haile selassie.
Where the lines cross is
the exact location of the city.
- And the idol?
- Ooh! I hates those questions.
I know what you’re thinking.
Me and thomas searched
and found nothing.
The idol’s a legend.
I hates legends.
[Laughter]
All right.
It’s been dead and gone
for more than 1,000 years.
But the cult is alive.
- Ooh!
- Yeah, the cult’s alive.
But its beliefs
are based on legends.
In time, the cult members
will find out of themselves.
And the cult
will gradually be dissolved.
And how many lives
will they claim
before this happens?
Go home.
Forget about the cult.
Don’t let it destroy
your life too.
It already has.
Look at my hair.
Wait! I was going to sing
something from bone machine.
If it’s any consolation,
I hates that rabbit too.
Well, who’s up
for a moose-lip omelet?
Don’t trust that man.
I remember him.
He was with satoris the night
your father was killed.
There’s the door.
I can just leave.
You don’t mean that--
killed your father?
Sounds fun, but i’m busy.
I don’t know.
Well, how about
a game of balderdash?
Ooh, fresh towels
in the guest room.
[Humming]
Nothing? Absolutely nothing?
Nope, nope. Sorry, crow.
But from everything
i’ve read here,
there’s nothing we can do
about hockey hair.
We just have to get
plenty of rest and hockey,
and let it
take care of itself.
All right.
[Together]
Whoa, mike! Aah! Sheesh!
- Hey, guys.
- Mike, what happened to you?
Oh, i’m just seeing
what it’s like to smoke a pipe.
No, no, no, it’s your hair.
It’s like, uh, it’s...
Look.
Aah! Whoa! Holy cow.
Don’t panic, now, mike.
You’ve simply got a case
of grizzled old
prospector syndrome.
- Whoa, man.
- It’s not surprising.
It is associated
with immunity to hockey hair.
Yeah, it may not even be
a full-blown infection.
Unless you’ve been saying
"consarn it" a lot.
- Nope, consarn it can’t--
- oh!
- Ah, dagnabbit!
- Oh!
Oh, well, fiddlesticks!
Little varmints.
I guess I am hornswoggled.
Well, what do you reckon
I should do about it?
Uh, let’s see...
Nothing to do, mike,
you just got to let it
run its course.
Yeah, you’ll want
to pan for gold, probably.
- You’ll probably buy a mule.
- Al right, well...
I wonder how I picked it up.
Well, let’s see, um...
You been kissing
any prospectors?
- Nope!
- Good, phew.
Hold on. Wait a minute.
- No, no, I haven’t. No.
- Phew.
Oh. No, you know what,
that was a surly truck farmer.
Darn fine kisser though.
You old coot, huh?
Uh, we’ll be right back.
Yee-hoo!
♪♪
- Dagnabbit.
- Cleared right up.
Ah, language camp
is so far away.
I’m taking you home tomorrow.
I know mom and dad
will just love you.
Hm?
Troy.
Man, you kill one guy’s dad.
I wonder if there’s beer
on the sun.
Rowsdower. [Snoring]
Ah, crusty pants,
a filthy wall, good morning.
Ah, man. Those 12 ounce curls
really take it out of me.
Have a drink on me, tattoo.
Leif garrett today.
Well, that’s enough
for one day. Ugh.
♪ Val-der-ee,
val-der-ah-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha ♪
Man, that’s
a terrible golf stroke.
I’ll plant the roses here.
Bleh! Aah! Ugh!
Um, sss!
He’s laying on a bear.
Hey, he got to second base
with himself.
Whoo!
Well, I got that done.
God bless mommy and daddy
and grandpa
and all my evil henchmen.
[Humming]
Aah, oh, another m.I.
Oh, great.
He’s invoking
the powers of bryan adams.
[Grunts]
One.
Bonanza.
Ugh, i’m exhausted.
I gotta take a nap
after i’m done sleeping.
Bless my stick,
oh, holy willie mosconi.
Oh, man, that’s not a nose,
that’s a duplex.
Hey!
Hey! Ah, this’ll teach me.
Hand me my top hat.
[Humming charge baseball song]
♪ Do-do-do-do do-do
charge ♪
All righty, the doctor
will be in to see you
in just a minute.
Ooh.
Aw, your s’more fell in.
♪ Ay-yi-yi
hey ♪
♪ ay-yi-yi-yi-yi
♪ ay-yi-yi
hey ♪
[Singing continues]
Vodka!
- Really?
- No.
I got ketchup on my hand.
[Sobbing]
Well, i’m not hiring these guys
to do my nipple piercing.
Aah!
Oh.
I forgot, the liquor stores
close at 8:00!
Sorry.
Troy?
Troy.
Now mike, technically
that paper is smokin!
- No!
- Sorry.
Kramer-dower.
They took him.
I gotta go work out.
Why?
Man, my lice
has left my beard.
What would they want
with the boy?
[Horse whinny]
Here, okay.
Having a hard time
saddling up the misses today.
I made you some trail mix
out of rat droppings and hair.
She’s old, but she’s got
lots of spirit.
Now ride, postman!
Look, I want
to come with you.
No. It’s too slow.
Whoa. But thanks
for everything.
The fleas and all, you know.
Head north until you get
to the river.
Follow it upstream.
[Horse whinnies]
The lone rowsdower.
[Humming the lone ranger theme]
Ow.
Yeah, yeah. I know the routine.
Now, the double jock-lock.
Oh, goodie. You’re going to ride
back here with me!
You guys know any camp songs?
[Humming]
Uh, sir, you know,
maybe if you got rid of
that huge gunnysack
of ground pork and--
oh, that’s your butt.
I’m sorry.
Excuse me a moment.
Plop, plop, plop, plop. Ah.
Meat. Ta-da.
Why couldn’t I have been bought
by a seventh-grade girl?
Hang on now,
it’s my turn to ride you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
mr. Alan jackson.
Erich von stroheim
hitches across america.
My glee-club
will be looking for me.
And for your friend rowsdower,
I hope he’s not late.
Else we shall have to
start without him.
He’ll be here...
To stop you.
[Laughs]
You pusses make me laugh.
- I like you, troy.
- Ew.
It is a pity
you have to die so soon.
You are so much
like your father.
Bright, stubborn...
Well, stubborn anyway.
And in my way.
Hang on, I gotta tinkle.
Who killed my father?
Why don’t you ask your friend
when he arrives?
Ha-ha! The jokes on you.
I don’t have any friends.
Hey, how did he get
get his pants clean?
Say what you want
about the filthy, grizzled guy,
he does a good load
of laundry.
[Humming, beatboxing]
♪ You got mud on your face,
you big disgrace ♪
♪ shoving those sandwiches
into your face ♪
♪ singing we will,
we will rowsdower ♪
Sing it!
♪ We will, we will... ♪
Rowsdower.
I guess that’s over.
Hello? Have you seen
the other hooded thugs?
Ah, he splashed around
a little thug musk
in the area to lure them.
Ah.
[Gunshot]
Oh, I shot
right in between them.
I got confused.
[Humming figaro’s aria]
Balanchine.
Gerard, go that way.
Robert, follow me.
Oh, michelle,
thierry, help me!
Smell my fingers!
♪♪ [Singing figaro]
A horse!
My six-pack for a horse.
Hey it turns out
to be mount pinatubo,
they all fall in.
The end. Bye!
No, no, no,
no you don’t junior.
- Get in here.
- Oh.
[Gasping, choking]
My heart!
♪♪
Oh, wow. It's
a stuart anderson's
cattle company cult.
- Keep quiet.
- My rowsdower’s come for me.
Mammy! Aah.
[Laughs]
I’m just remembering
a scene from bio-dome.
Cut yourself loose.
Hurry up.
I dropped it.
My men will not disturb us.
They’re closing off
all avenues of escape.
Don’t worry,
we won’t hurt you.
You fear me.
Perhaps you remember
your last defeat.
Aah!
Hey, I wasn’t done.
Ow!
What is this, a grappling hook
dumping ground?
Fire better not
get near his mousse.
Which is the sharp side?
Hey, this is it.
This is the actual
crazy world of arthur brown.
Um, I cut both my wrists.
SEVEN YEARS AGO, YOU FOUGHT ME
TRYING TO SAVE THOMAS McGREGGOR.
Now you fight
to save his son.
Well, you started it!
You killed him,
and left me alive
to torment
for the rest of my life.
- Hm?
- What?
McGREGGOR REFUSED
TO COOPERATE.
He had to die.
You were guilty of a crime
much worse than his.
You broke the sole law
of our society.
You left.
Death would be too merciful
for you, zap rowsdower.
Zap!
I chose to let you live
to be tormented by our drums
until the end
of your miserable life.
Aah!
Uh, I somehow
swallowed the knife!
And i’m really mad
that you never do the dishes
when it’s your turn!
Oh, nice, are those totes?
Oh, hey, they are!
You are mine.
[Gunshot]
Ow. You shot my butt.
What the hell?
You shot me in the butt!
You will be
the last sacrifice.
The last one between me
and ultimate power
over the earth.
Oh, wait,
there’s one guy after you.
So you’re--
you’re second to last.
[Growling]
[Yawns]
So, mike, most humans,
when you shoot them in the butt,
they burst into flames?
Well, I don’t know.
- Can we try it? Turn around.
- Yeah, come on.
No.
You all right, kid?
Well, I don’t have many friends,
girls don’t like me,
and my teachers absolutely
hate-- oh, yeah i’m fine.
[Thunder claps]
Somewhere, lee trevino
scurries for cover.
[Mooing]
The legend goes,
if the idol is ever destroyed,
then the city will return
to its former glory.
Uh-huh.
It’s a symbol of good,
and will mean
the end of satoris.
And remember, if the ladies
don’t find your handsome,
at least you should be handy.
Stay with me, troy,
and i’ll guide you in the ways
of alcohol,
cigarettes, and meat.
Well, it was a pretty good cult,
but hockey’s season’s
starting and all.
Okay, hood-washing time guys.
Let’s just do them
all in one load.
They’re all the same color.
So, ted, you think we’re going
to get paid for this week?
[Chuckles]
Somebody reboot the kid.
The love canal state forest.
[Creaking]
Hey, i’m in a snowmobile club
with that one guy.
Rowsdower!
So their city’s
a pop-out greeting card.
That’s not actually a lost city,
it was just unclaimed.
Rowsdower.
Wow, it’s expo ’67.
A whole nother city
to fail in.
I wonder if they need
snow plowing services.
Audrey hepburn--
oh, it’s troy.
Well, son of a buck,
that just flew up there.
Luke, it is your destiny.
Hm?
Susan dey!
Oh, no, it’s troy. Sorry.
He’s gonna turn
into a war-wilf.
How about a smoke, kid?
Hey, the neosporin
really worked.
All right!
My drinkin’ arm’s healed!
Uh, rowsdower,
you’re squeezing my--
row-- [cracking sounds]
Rowsdower. Row...
Ooh, that shot
contains too much nostril.
Oh, heck, I can’t believe
the ancient city
kicked us out already.
Join us next week
when troy and zap battle
an army of evil acadian robots
on cape breton.
Then in upcoming weeks,
they’ll take on
a band of zombie fur trappers
in medicine hat.
That’s on zap and troy,
the legendary journeys.
[Humming]
♪ Oh, baby,
rowsdower saves us ♪
♪ and saves all the world ♪
♪ he comes to save the day
in a broken truck ♪
♪ with a stinky denim jacket
on his back ♪
♪ he couldn’t help this movie
which really sucked ♪
♪ but at least we didn’t have to
see him play hackeysack ♪
What?
I’m sorry, I panicked.
Wake up. This is
important to me damnit.
Well, i’ll try to do better.
Ssh, here it comes. Listen.
♪ Rowsdower saves us ♪
♪ and saves all the world ♪
♪ rowsdower saves-- ♪
No, no, no, mike,
that section’s over,
you non-musical mook.
- Well, sorry.
- Never mind.
I’ll handle
this section myself.
Talk quietly
amongst yourselves.
♪ Danny elfman,
danny elfman ♪
♪ this song sounds
like danny elfman ♪
♪ it just sounds
like danny elfman
danny elfman ♪
♪ he’s the dad of jenna elfman,
jenna elfman, jenna elfman ♪
♪ he’s the daughter
of danny elfman ♪
♪ danny elfman,
danny elfman ♪
Say, mike, you know,
I didn’t think this movie
was as bad as the usual fare.
You’re joking I hope.
No, no, no.
Admittedly it had some flaws.
It was a little overzealous
pursuing some of its ideas,
granted, but I think it was
more of a problem of form.
A movie is just not
the right medium
for this material.
It needs tv.
It needs to be a series.
Hm, I don’t know.
Just let me
pitch this to you.
Uh, okay, i’m listening. Go.
Great, great,
thanks for hearing me out.
Okay, the final sacrifice,
the series.
- The name goes.
- What?
Never liked the name.
The name goes. It’s banal.
But if you’re hoping
to connect the series
with the movie, mike--
we need something like,
oh, night mistress.
Night mistress?
Yeah, or clootchi
and the lieutenant.
You know, something
that’s going to seduce people.
Really connect with them.
We’ll work on that.
Okay. Okay...
So you got rowsdower,
and he roams through canada,
and he’s got
his little pal troy,
and they all get into
all kinds of scrapes.
- But they help people--
- alabama.
- What?
- Alabama, chicago, cleveland.
No, I like alabama.
You like alabama?
It’s your show.
Well, to me,
canada is the essence--
pittsburgh, we’ll do it
in pittsburgh.
Well, I suppose if you actually
film it in pittsburgh--
no, no, no, we film in canada.
Have to.
[Beep]
Hold on. Yeah, judy.
Okay, thanks.
You got two minutes.
Guttenberg’s people
are coming in.
What do you mean
guttenberg’s people
are coming in?
What I mean is
you just lost a minute. Go.
Whoa, sorry, sorry.
So, the lead character
is rowsdower, of course.
LEAD CHARACTER’S THE KID,
SPARKY McHOOLIHAN
or whatever the hell
his name was.
You like that name?
I never liked that name.
Well, that’s not his name.
I mean...
But I like all that
funny beer stuff you get
with that rowsdower guy.
Him being a hopeless drunk
and all that.
He’s loveable, you know?
He falls down, he’s sick a lot,
but he’s loveable.
And the kid,
the kid works in a brewery.
I actually had
an hour-long drama in mind.
What are you, one of those
dennis franz freaks, huh?
Now, wait a minute--
wait, wait, wait, yeah,
give me a second here.
I’m going somewhere.
I’m there, i’m there.
This rowsdower guy,
full frontal, you know?
Couple times a season.
Tasteful, low lights,
just a hint.
[Beep]
Hold on. Yes, judy.
I know. You got 30 seconds.
Okay, well this main character,
um, sparky--
has a friend, a girl.
Hell, he’s a girl too.
There are a lot of girls.
They’re all roommates.
There’s a goofy girl,
a serious girl,
a cheerleader,
the loose girl.
Everybody in the damn series
is a damn girl!
- Yeah, but rowsdower--
- a big, hairy girl!
[Beep]
Yes, judy. I’ll tell you what.
I got a show idea for you.
You get out of my office
until you give me something
I can use.
-Now I gotta go meet
gutenberg’s people.
- Whoa!
Gee whiz.
[Humming continues]
Hey, where’s the music?
You guys!
The end!
We shall meet at midnight,
and then--
- hello, mike.
- Hi, fellas. How’s it going?
- Nice flowers.
- Thanks.
Hey! You guys didn’t take and go
and start a cult, did you?
[Coughs]
A cult?
A cult? No, of course not.
That is the most absurd thing--
well, yeah we did.
Yeah, you want to join?
No, I don’t want to join.
You’ll probably be sacrificing
black pullets,
and wearing goat heads
and things.
Well, you know,
we thought about all that,
but it just seemed
like a lot of work.
Actually we just
like to bake muffins.
Lots of different kinds.
Yeah, then we get together
at each other’s houses,
AND WATCH ALLY McBEAL.
Or one of our collection
of taped sisters episodes.
Yeah, we’re kind of
a muffiney,
calista flockheart,
swoosie kurtz kind of cult.
Yeah.
Um, mike?
Oh, boy.
I think we freaked him out.
Whoa. Okay, mike.
We strip to the waist,
worship an evil emanation,
and lop people’s heads off
for fun.
Is that less weird?
Ah, yeah, that’s
a little easier to take.
- Good.
- Oh, uh, pearl’s calling.
[Growling]
Ah, nelson.
So glad we could join you.
For, you see, I am about to take
a giant step forward
in my program
to take over the world,
one person at a time.
After hours
of tough negotiation,
I am about to possess
the mind,
the soul, the very will
of this man here.
What was your name again?
Carl.
All right, carl.
You’ve cowered
at my threats,
you’ve relished my rewards,
you’ve eaten me out
of house and home,
now sign.
Certainly, my liege.
[Phone ringing]
Hang on. Let me get this.
Yeah. Really?
How much?
Sounds good. Thanks.
I’m sorry, lady.
I was just taken over
by the travelers group.
Gotta run. Bye.
- Monkey, whitey...
- We’re on it.
I guess the mrs. Mr. Nice guy
approach just ain’t my style.
[Cackles]
So very shortly now, nelson,
I will rule carl!
Untie me or you’ll have to
answer to the travelers group!
Give me back my food!
No! Ugh!
♪♪
Rowsdower.